### John Patrick O'Connor PhD.

M: Johnoc4389@gmail.com Ph: +61 0420588837 A: 14 25 Partridge street, Glenelg, South Australia 5045 I am a mechanical engineer with several years experience in product development, manufacturing and mechanical design. I have a wide knowledge of system and component development for several types of systems from electronics to medical devices. I am looking for opportunities in academia in the medical device field or research opportunities in that area.

## **Professional Experience**

2018-2020 Johnson & Johnson 3D Printing, Cork Ireland, Senior Engineer 3D-Printing

• Senior engineer responsible for development of 3D-printed Titanium orthopaedic implants. Acting technical lead for several successful projects. Provided modelling, measurement & manufacturing expertise to the team and wider 3D-printing group in Johnson & Johnson. Provide sample and preparation material for surgeon labs. Managed industry partner projects for EU funded project – ENCOMPASS. Developed several patents in medical device field for 3D-printed orthopaedic implants.

2017–2018 Elvesys SAS, Paris France, Research Associate

• Research associate responsible for managing EU project-BIOCUDET. Developed thermofludic system for rapid real time PCR machine ( $\leq 10$ min) which lead to the creation of the start-up company B4Cure. Managed team of junior engineers and scientists to meet project goals.

2016–2017 Microchip (Formally MicroSemi), Ennis Ireland, Research & Development Engineer

• Lead product development of new surface mount transient voltage suppressor array package. Developed and tested product to military specification MIL-STD 17500. Created finite element model of semiconductor packaging to MIL STD 17500 and JEDEC standards.

#### Education

2012 - 2017University of Limerick Ireland – PhD. in Mechanical Engineering 2007-2011 University of Limerick Ireland – B.Eng in Mechanical Engineering

- Doctoral Thesis: Thermal Hydraulic characterisation of obstacles in microchannel flow: The influence of confinement
- Undertook teaching assistant roles for several engineering courses
- Completed 3-month internship with industry partner sponsoring doctoral studies

#### Core Skills & Competencies

- - Finite Element Modelling
- 3D-Printing
- Optical Measurement Techniques

- Programming
- CAD modelling Manufacturing Techniques
- Experimental Design
- Microscopy

#### **Research Interests**

- Transport Phenomena Energy Storage
- Additive Manufacturing

- Microfluidics
- Organ-on-a-chip Medical Device

# **Key Publications**

- A dimensional comparison between embedded 3D-printed and silicon microchannels. Journal of Physics: Conference Series 525 012009
- A comparison between the hydrodynamic characteristics of 3D-printed polymer and etched silicon microchannels. Microfluidics and Nanofluidics 19(2), 385-394